chapter 35 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public domain Black
Beauty by Anna suell chapter 35 Jerry Barker I never knew a better man than my
new master. He was kind and good, and as strong for the right as John Manley and
so good-tempered and merry that very few people could pick a quarrel with him. He
was very fond of making little songs, and singing them to himself. One he was very
fond of was this: “Come, father and mother, And sister and brother, Come, all of you,
turn to And help one another.” And so they did; Harry was as
clever at stable work as a much older boy, and always wanted to do what he
could. Then Polly and Dolly used to come in the morning to help with the cab— —to
brush and beat the cushions, and rub the glass, while Jerry was giving us a
cleaning in the yard, and Harry was rubbing the harness. There used to be a great deal of
laughing and fun between them, and it put Captain and me in much better spirits
than if we had heard scolding and hard words. They were always early in the
morning, for Jerry would say: “If you in the morning Throw minutes away, You can't
pick them up In the course of a day. You may hurry and scurry, And flurry and
worry, You've lost them forever, Forever and I He could not bear any careless
loitering and waste of time; and nothing was so near making him angry as to find
people, who were always late, wanting a cab horse to be driven hard, to make up for their
idleness. One day two wild looking young men came out of a tavern close to the
stand, and called Cherry Here cabie look sharp, we are rather late; put on the
steam, will you, and take us to the Victoria in time for the 1:00 train? You
shall have a shilling extra.” “I will take you at the regular
pace, gentlemen; shillings don't pay for putting on the steam like
that.” Larry's cab was standing next to hours he flung open the door, and said,
“I'm your man, gentlemen! take my cab, my horse will get you there all right;” and
as he shut them in, with a wink toward Jerry, said, “It's against his conscience
to go beyond a jog Trot Then slashing his jaded horse, he set off as hard as he
could. Jerry patted me on the neck: “No, Jack, a shilling would not pay for that
sort of thing, would it, old boy?” Although Jerry was determinedly set
against hard driving, to please careless people, he always went a good fair pace,
and was not against putting on the steam, as he said, if only he knew why.
I well remember one morning, as we were on the stand waiting for a fair that a
young man, carrying a heavy portmanto trod on a piece of orange peel which lay
on the pavement, and fell down with great force. Jerry was the first to run and
lift him up. He seemed much stunned, and as they led him into a shop he walked as
if he were in great pain. Jerry of course came back to the stand, but in about 10
minutes one of the shopmen called him, so we drew up to the
pavement. “Can you take me to the Southeastern Railway?” said the young man;
“this unlucky fall has made me late, I fear; but it is of great importance that
I should not lose the 12:00 train. I should be most thankful if you could get
me there in time, and will gladly pay you an extra Fair I'll do my very best,” said
Jerry heartily, “if you think you are well enough, sir,” for he looked dreadfully white and
ill. “I must go,” he said earnestly, “please to open the door, and let us lose no
time.” The next minute Jerry was on the box; with a cheery cherup to me, and a
twitch of the rain that I well understood. “Now then, Jack, my boy,” said he,
“spin along, we'll show them how we can get over the ground, if we only know
why.” It is always difficult to drive fast in the city in the middle of the day,
when the streets are full of traffic, but we did what could be done; and when a
good drive and a good horse, who understand each other, are of one mind, it
is wonderful what they can do. I had a very good mouth— —that is I
could be guided by the slightest touch of the rain and that is a great thing in
London, among carriages, omnibuses, carts, vans, trucks, cabs, and great wagons
creeping along at a walking pace; some going one way, some another, some going
slowly, others wanting to pass them omnibus is stopping short every few
minutes to take up a passenger, obliging the horse that is coming behind to pull
up two or to pass, and get before them; perhaps you try to pass, but just then
something else comes dashing in through the narrow opening, and you have to keep
in behind the omnibus again; presently you think you see a chance, and manage to
get to the front, going so near the wheels on each side that half an inch
nearer and they would scrape. Well, you get along for a bit, but
soon find yourself in a long train of carts and carriages all obliged to go at
a walk; perhaps you come to a regular block up and have to stand still for
minutes together, till something clears out into a side street, or the policeman
interferes; you have to be ready for any chance— —to dash forward if there be an
opening, and be quick as a rat dog to see
if there be room and if there be time, lest you get your own wheels locked or
smashed, or the shaft of some other vehicle run into your chest or
shoulder all All this is what you have to be ready for. If you want to get
through London fast in the middle of the day it wants a deal of
practice. Jerry and I were used to it, and no one could beat us at getting through
when we were set upon it. I was quick and bold and could always trust my driver;
Jerry was quick and patient at the same time, and could trust his horse, which was
a great thing too. He very seldom used the whip; I knew
by his voice voice and his click, click, when he wanted to get on fast, and by the
rain where I was to go; so there was no
need for whipping; but I must go back to my story. The streets were very full that
day, but we got on pretty well as far as the bottom of Cheapside, where there was
a block for 3 or 4 minutes. The young man put his head out
and said anxiously, “I think I had better get out and walk; I shall never get there
if this goes on I shall do all that can be done, sir,”
said Jerry; “I think we shall be in time.
This block up cannot last much longer, and your luggage is very heavy for you to carry,
sir.” Just then the cart in front of us
began to move on, and then we had a good
turn. In and out, in and out we went, as
fast as horse flesh could do it, and for a wonder had a good clear time on London
Bridge, for there was a whole train of cabs and carriages all going our way at
a quick trot, perhaps wanting to catch that very train. At any rate, we welled into the
station with many more, just as the great clock pointed 8 minutes to
12:00 Thank God! we are in time,” said the young man, “and thank you, too, my friend,
and your good horse. You have saved me more than money can ever pay for. Take
this extra half crown No, sir, no, thank you all the same;
so glad we hit the time, sir; but don't stay now, sir, the bell is ringing. Here,
porter! take this gentleman's luggage doline 12:00 train— —that's it,” and without
waiting for another word Jerry wheeled me round to make room for other cabs
that were dashing up at the last minute, and drew up on one side till the crush was
passed So glad!' he said, 'so glad!' Poor young fellow! I wonder what it was that
made him so anxious!” Jerry often talked to himself quite loud enough for me to hear when we
were not moving. On Jerry's return to the rank there was a good deal of laughing and
chafing at him for driving hard to the train for an extra Fair as they said, all
against his principles, and they wanted to know how much he had
pocketed. “A good deal more than I generally get,” said he, nodding slightly
what he gave me will keep me in little comforts for several
days Gom said one. “He's a humbug,” said another; “preaching to us and then doing the same
himself.” “Look here, mates,” said Jerry; “the gentleman offered me half a crown extra,
but I didn't take it it was quite pay
enough for me to see how glad he was to catch that train; and if Jack and I
choose to have a quick run now and then to please ourselves, that's our business and not
yours.” “Well,” said Larry, “you'll never be a rich manmost likely not,” said Jerry;
“but I don't know that I shall be the less happy for that. I have heard the
commandments read a great many times and I never noticed that any of them said,
'Thou shalt be rich'; and there are a good many curious things said in the New
Testament about rich men that I think would make me feel rather queer if I was one of
them.” “If you ever do get rich,” said Governor Gray, looking over his shoulder
across the top of his cab, “you'll deserve it, Jerry, and you won't find a curse come
with your wealth. As for you, Larry, you'll die poor; you spend too much in whip
cord Well,” said Larry, “what is a fellow to do if his horse won't go without
it?” “You never take the trouble to see if he will go without it; your whip is
always going as if you had the St Vitter dance in your arm, and if it does not
wear you out it wears your horse out; you know you are always changing your horses;
and why? Because you never give them any peace or encouragement.” “Well, I have not had good
luck,” said Larry, “that's where it is.” “And you never will,” said the governor.
“Good Luck is rather particular who she rides with, and mostly prefers those who
have got common sense and a good heart; at least that is my
experience.” Governor Gray turned round again to his newspaper, and the other men went to their
cabs end of chapter